# SHELLBY J. MILLER

4443 Lyons Rd Phone: (478) 955-4169

Stonecrest, Georgia 30032 E-mail: shellby.miller@gmail.com

GIS Analyst with four and a half years of experience working with ArcGIS Suite and ArcGIS Pro software for developing and maintaining geodatabases and performing spatial analyses. Highly organized individual with a passionate work ethic.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Senior Data & GIS Analyst

Atlanta Regional Commission

December 2021-Present

- Manages GIS needs of Natural Resources Group
- Performs research, collects, organizes, and analyzes data to meet programmatic needs of group
- Manages cooperative River-Lake Information Management System
- Organizes and facilitates meetings with stakeholder utilities in the Advanced Metering Infrastructure group
- Develops and maintains web-based interactive tools for Natural Resources Group
- Provides technical guidance to support users of web-based interactive tools

GIS Analyst July 2020-Present

Middle Georgia Regional Commission

- Performed tax parcel maintenance and CUVA analysis for Tax Assessors
- Created and maintained hosted web layers, web maps, and web apps
- Created and edited versioned data on Spatial Database Engines
- Submitted Boundary Annexation Survey for local governments
- Refined road centerline data for NextGen911 and Roadway Element Validation and Mapping Program

## Natural Resources GIS Intern & Program Assistant

2019-2020

Atlanta Regional Commission

Source Water Assessment Plan

- Performed spatial analyses in ArcGIS Pro to assign risk rankings to potential pollutant sources
- Developed a methodology for risk assessment of pollutants to surface water intakes
- Assisted in writing the updated 2020 Source Water Assessment Plan
- Coordinated and meet with local utilities to discuss their unique reports

#### Toilet Rebate Program

- Managed program data for a metro district wide rebate program
- Analyzed indoor water use data to determine efficiency measures
- Processed paperwork pertaining to rebate applications

## **Graduate Research & Teaching Assistant**

2018-2019

Department of Geosciences, Georgia State University

- Conducted research on the efficiency of urban beaver dams to attenuate pollution introduced by effluent
- Instructed undergraduate students in an introductory course
- Assisted in redesigning of lab activities
- Graded lab assignments and quizzes

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Georgia State University**

December 2019

M.S., Geosciences GPA: 4.15 Concentration: Water Sciences

Professional Certificate, Geographical Information Science

Advisor: Dr. Sarah Ledford

### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

2016

B.S., Earth and Atmospheric Sciences

Focus in Environmental Science with Research Option in Climate Change

Advisor: Dr. Kim Cobb

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

ArcGIS Pro, ArcGIS Suite 10.x, Python, SQL Server, MATLAB, ERDAS IMAGINE, Microsoft Office Suite, Time Management, Communication and Public Speaking, Adaptability, Interpersonal Skills, Detailed Oriented

## **PRESENTATIONS**

American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting

Fall 2019

Poster Presentation San Francisco, CA

Georgia Tech Undergraduate Research Symposium

Spring 2015, 2016

Oral Presentation

Atlanta, GA

American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting

Fall 2015

Poster Presentation San Francisco, CA

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Georgia Geospatial Association	Fall 2020-Present
Atlanta Region Geospatial Community	Spring 2019-Present
500 Women Scientists, Member	Fall 2016-Present
Geoscience Graduate Student Alliance, Co-President	Fall 2018-2020
Geological Society of America, Member	Fall 2018-2020
American Geophysical Union, Member	Fall 2015-Present